Yan Xiang

 \clubsuit https://yx-hci.github.io/ | \blacksquare yanxiang@sjtu.edu.cn | \thickapprox Yan Xiang | \blacksquare +(65)83516957

Research Interests

My broad research interests include Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Human-AI Interaction (HAI), and AR & VR, and their application to user-centered programming, multi-modal human perception and engagement, as well as data-driven approach to human-centered design and computing.

Education

Shanghai Jiao Tong University (SJTU), Shanghai, China Sep. 2021 - Mar. 2024 (Expected) Master of Engineering in International Industrial Design Engineering (English Program), School of Design GPA: 3.92/4.0, Rank: 2/39 (Top 5%), Outstanding Graduate Scholarship (Top 0.5%)

Northeastern University (NEU), Shenyang, China Bachelor of Engineering in Architecture, School of Architecture GPA: 88.20/100, Rank: 3/66 (Top 5%), Provincial Outstanding Graduate (Top 1%)

Singapore University of Technology and Design (SUTD), Singapore Sep. 2023 - Jan. 2024 Visiting Student, Data-Driven Innovation Lab, Engineering Product Development Pillar

Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, South Korea Sep. 2018 - Jun. 2019 Exchange Student, Architecture, Department of Architecture & Architectural Engineering GPA: 3.83/4.3 (94.30/100)

Bauhaus-Universität Weimar, Weimar, Germany Summer Institute, Architecture and Urbanism

Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2021

Publications

ISTE '22	Xiang, Y., Chang, D., Yao, Y., Wang, L., et al. (2022). "Usability Evaluation of Elder-Friendly Design: Application to Take Alipay App." In <i>Transdisciplinarity and the Future of Engineering</i> (pp. 154-163), IOS Press. https://doi.org/10.3233/ATDE220642.
DIS '23 WiP	Xiang, Y., Fan, Q., Qian, K., Li. J., et al. (2023). "Decentralized Governance for Virtual Community (DeGov4VC): Optimal Policy Design of Human-plant Symbiosis Co-creation." In DIS'23 Companion: Companion Publication of the 2023 ACM Designing Interactive Sys-

Chang, D., Xiang, Y., Zhao, J., Qian, Y., & Li, F. (2022). "Exploration of Brain-Computer Interaction for Supporting Children's Attention Training: A Multimodal Design Based on Attention Network and Gamification Design.", International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(22), 15046. (SCI, JCR Q1, First student author). https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph192215046.

tems Conference (pp.207-212). https://doi.org/10.1145/3563703.3596621.

- Xiang, Y., Chang, D., Feng, X. (2023). "Leveraging Urban Big Data for Informed Business Location Decisions: A Case Study of Starbucks in Tianhe District, Guangzhou City.", In 2023 IEEE International Conference on Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management (IEEM), IEEE. (Accepted). http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.09778.
- Xiang, Y., Chang, D., Cheng, J. (2023). "Exploring the Correlation between Urban Microclimate Simulation and Urban Morphology: A Case Study in Yeongdeungpo-gu, Seoul.", In 2023 IEEE International Conference on Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management (IEEM), IEEE (Accepted). http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.09779.
- Comput Xiang, Y., Zhang, Z., Chang, D., Tu, L. (2023). "The Impact of Gamified Auditory-Verbal Educ Training for Hearing-Challenged Children at Intermediate and Advanced Rehabilitation Stages." Computers & Education. (SCI, Under Review). http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11047.

- CHI '24 Zhang, J.*, Xiang, Y.*, Zhao, Y.*, Jin, X., ... & LC, R. (2024). "From Design Inspiration to Co-curation: The Changing Role of Curatorial Practice in a Digital Generative AI Landscape for the Arts.", In 2024 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. (Under Review, *Co-first Authors).
- HRI '24 Xiang, Y. (2024). "A System Design for Multi-Modal Emotion Regulation and Management in Human-Robot and Human-Computer Interactions." In 2024 19th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction. (Under Review).
- IMWUT '24 Zhou, C., Ram, A., Gu, Y., ... & Xiang, Y. (2024). "GlassMail: Towards Personalised Wearable Assistant for On-the-go Email Creation on Smart Glasses." *Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies.* (Submitted).
- Preprint Chang, D., Xiang, Y.*, Zhu, X. (2023). "A Style Matching Approach for the Generative Design of Animated Posters." (Preprint, *Co-first authors and corresponding author).

Research Experience

Information and Interaction Lab @ School of Design, SJTU

Research Assistant, Advisor: Prof. Danni Chang, Prof. Zhenyu Gu

Sept. 2021 - Present

Gamified Brain-Computer Interface for Attention-Impaired Children's Training [More Details]

- Developed a multimodal BCI attention training system for children through real-time EEG command.
- Independently completed the design and development of training game with Unity based on C#.
- Verified by the experiment that the system significantly improves the users' attention behaviors (p<0.05).
- Accepted by the IJERPH as the first student author.

Usability Evaluation and Improvement for Elder-Friendly App Design [More Details]

- Applied Alipay's elder-friendly mode to tackle the usability and learnability problem through experiment.
- Analyzed eye movement data, derived design strategies through information architecture, task flow and UI.
- Accepted by the ISTE '23 Conference as the first author, orally presented in MIT, Cambridge, USA.

Auditory-Verbal Training System Design for Hearing-Challenged Children [More Details]

- Designed gamefied training system for children in intermediate and advanced hearing rehabilitation stage.
- Utilized voice and facial mouth shape recognition technology in developing the training system.
- Enhanced the auditory speech rehabilitation training in improving language abilities (n=31, p<0.05).
- Submitted to the Computers and Education as the first author.

Style Matching Approach for Generative Design of Animated Posters [More Details]

- Applied Kansei Engineering to create a dynamic style labeling dataset by generating and labeling samples.
- Trained a BP neural network and combined genetic algorithm for animated style-matching model.
- Conducted comparative experiments, validated the parametric generation model's validity and usability (p<0.05).

Brain Computer Interface Lab @ Rui Jin Hospital Clinical Neuroscience Center

Research Assistant, Advisor: Dr. Odin van der Stelt, Prof. Baoliang LU

Oct. 2022 - June 2023

Investigating Digital Therapeutics and Designing PD-CAT for Parkinson's Disease

- Conducted research on digital health products for elderly and designed experimental paradigms.
- Developed a Parkinson's disease cognitive assessment and training tool on mobile and wearable devices.
- Experimentally verified significant improvement in cognitive clinical patient behavior (p<0.05).

Multimodal Emotional Human-space Interaction via Brain-Computer Interaction [More Details]

- Developed a multimodal emotion recognition and regulation service system for space through bio-signal.
- Designed a real-time adjustment model based on brain-computer interaction through EEG signal.
- Verified the effectiveness by conducting experiment with participants in Shanghai Mental Health Center.
- Submitted to the HRI '24 Conference as the first author.

Data-Driven Innovation Lab @ Singapore University of Technology and Design

Visiting Student, Advisor: Prof. Jianxi Luo

Sept. 2023 - Jan. 2024 (Expected)

Chatbot as an Advisor for Designer through Large Language Models

- Developed a system and framework through prompt-based learning using the GPT-4 and DALL·E API.
- Designed and developed an empathetic chatbot for engaging user interactions and visualize user status.
- Utilized language inference techniques to generate and enhance users' knowledge systems within the design.

MIT Media Lab-City Science Lab @ Shanghai

Research Assistant, Advisor: Dr. Yan Zhang (Ryan), Prof. Kent Larson

Sept. 2021 - Aug. 2023

Human-AI Co-creation System Design for Decentralized VR Community [More Details]

- Proposed a decentralized governance model for a virtual community and designed an optimal symbiosis policy.
- Developed a co-creation DAO and evaluated co-design impact through AI agent-based simulation.
- Co-organized the MIT City Science Submit & SocityDAO workshop as one of the main mentors (1/10).
- Accepted by the DIS '23 Conference as work in progress as the first author.

NUS-HCI Lab, Department of Computer Science @ National University of Singapore

Research Assistant, Advisor: Prof. Shengdong (Shen) Zhao

May 2023 - Oct. 2023

Enhancing Empathetic Interaction through Heads-up Computing by AR Glasses

- Investigated how multimodal modes of emotional messages impact users' perception through AR glasses.
- Proposed effective co-creation methods and tool for empathic communication through AIGC technique.
- Validated that the proposed system facilitates deeper emotional interaction experiences.

Pervasive Human Computer Interaction Lab @ Tsinghua University

Summer Research, Advisor: Prof. Xin Yi, Prof. Yuntao Wang

May 2023- Sep. 2023

Facilitating Interaction with AIGC Using Proactive Feedback

- Investigated how users perceive and respond to empathetic and unconventional expressions from AI agents.
- Developed proactive feedback mechanism through 8 personality utilizing prompt engineering technology.
- Contrasted experiments on arousal and valence dimensions, revealing improved user emotional engagement.

HCI-X Summer Research @ CityU & DKU & HKUST(GZ)

Summer Research, Advisor: Prof. Ray LC, Prof. Xin Tong, Prof. Mingming Fan June 2023 - Sep. 2023

Exploring Human-AI Co-creation Approach in Digital Space and VR Exhibitions [More Details]

- Interviewed and encoded curators' insights into how the AIGC tool affects the digital curation experience.
- Created guidelines enabling curators to employ AIGC tools in different Human-AI co-curation processes.
- Validated the proposed design toolkit through experiments and hosted an open virtual exhibition online.

Teaching Assistantship

User Study international course (taught in English), SJTU, Shanqhai, China

Sep. 2022 - Jan.2023

- Conducted instruction classes on data analysis using SPSS and MATLAB to graduate students.
- Advised and assessed weekly assignments for 38 domestic and international graduate students.

Leadership & Innovation

• Delegate, Shape Machine Symposium @Georgia Tech & SNU, Seoul, South Korea	July 2019
• Exhibitor, "Third Space", exhibited in the Seoul Biennale of Architecture and Urbanism	Nov. 2019
• Delegate, ICDF Conference, China-Italy Design Innovation Hub, Tsinghua University	Nov. 2021
• Representative, Roundtable Talk, WDO World Industrial Design Day	June 2022
• Oral speaker, ISTE Conference, MIT Wong Auditorium, Cambridge, MA, USA	July 2022
• Delegate, Brain-Computer Interface & Neurotechnology Spring School, IEEE Brain	Apr. 2023
• Independent Exhibitor, "Twisting", exhibited in World Expo Museum, Shanghai	Nov. 2022
• Founder, "Neuro-Emotive", Invested by Prof. Zexiang LI (Former Chair of DJI)	May 2023 - Present

Skills

- Language: English (proficient), Cantonese (proficient), Mandarin Chinese (native)
- Experimental skills: Eye-tracking, and EEG-based brain-computer interface in data processing
- Professional skills: Python, Unity, Unreal Engine, C#, React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, SPSS, R